Peko Chuang / 莊孟璇

Front-End Developer

💌 peko.claire@gmail.com | 📞 0966-096-280 | 🕥 GitHub | in LinkedIn



Summary

As an optimistic and energetic Front-End Developer, I embrace challenges with enthusiasm, quickly extracting logical patterns and applying them to projects, completing tasks ahead of schedule. I enjoy brainstorming to craft practical solutions and enhance user experience.

Skills

Language	Framework and Library		Develop Tool
JavaScript (ES6+)TypeScriptCSSHTML	Next.js (App router)ReactReact RouterTailwindBootstrapStyled Components	Redux (Redux Toolkit)TiptapChart.js	GitGitHubPrettierESLintFirebaseVercel

Work Experience

AppWorks School – Front-End Developer

Mar 2023 ~ Aug 2023

- Adopted the Agile Scrum methodology to complete <u>personal project</u> in 5 weeks, achieved the development of a programming learning website ahead of schedule.
- Collaborated with the iOS team and Back-End team, participated in feature innovation discussions, and developed seller and native signup features based on the existing code base. [Demo Video]
- Engaged in frontend-related workshops and presented topics about <u>React reconciliation</u>, <u>floating-point numbers</u>, and <u>TypeScript</u>.
- Accepted into the coding bootcamp with a 10% acceptance rate.
- Strengthened to be a problem-solving active learner through intensive programming training, dedicating 75+ hours per week in software development.

Keelung Chang Gung Hospital – Respiratory Therapist Intern

Feb 2022 ~ Apr 2022

- Independently executed respiratory care of ICU patients, demonstrating exceptional critical thinking and adaptability in high-pressure environment.
- Collaborated with fellow caregivers, offering professional insights from a respiratory therapist
 perspective to determine the most suitable treatment.
- Engaged in case reports and research to stay updated on the latest medical advancements and discuss optimal treatment approaches.

Projects

Perky - Demo | GitHub

A programming learning community that fosters continuous knowledge sharing and peer learning through article interactions and online book clubs.

- Built with Next.js, enhancing the user experience through server components and server-side rendering.
- Made use of **React Redux** for centralized state management.
- Applied Tailwind to complete the RWD layout for both desktop and mobile devices.
- Utilized TypeScript for type checks and ESLint to develop reliable and maintainable code.
- Shared **React** components to improve code reusability and enable cleaner code.
- Leveraged Chart.js to demonstrate data in the form of a line chart.
- Implemented the third-party service VideoSdk to enable multi-conference meetings in book clubs.
- Integrated data with Firebase Firestore.

STYLiSH - Demo | GitHub

An E-commerce website with search, checkout, and Facebook login features.

- Utilized Styled Components to complete the RWD layout.
- Accomplished SPA with React Router.
- Developed with Third-party APIs (FB login, TapPay)
- · Connected APIs to fetch data from the database.
- · Leveraged Vanilla JavaScript to achieve feature of infinite scroll and carousel.

Wordle - Demo | GitHub

A challenging and fun word guessing game, where users get 6 chances to guess a 5-letter word.

• Utilized useReducer hook for state management.

Personal Website - <u>Demo</u> | <u>GitHub</u>

A website showcasing my side projects, social media links, and contact information.

Utilized EmailJS to send contact emails.

Education

Chung Gung University - Department of Respiratory Therapy

Sep 2018 ~ Jun 2022

GPA: 3.84 / 4.0

· Vice President of Respiratory Therapy Student Council

Other Skills

TOIEC: 840 / 990

Coursera:

• Python for Everybody Specialization - University of Michigan

Concepts for data retrieval, processing, and visualization data using Python.

· Version Control - Meta

Create effective software development workflow with Git and GitHub using Linux commands.